Finding Aid for the Photographers' Collection LSC.0098
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Shelflist
  - ***Barbara Morgan Exhibition Collection. v.p., v.d.; 144 items. Mounted salon print photographs. (Box 125, Box 126, Box 127, Box 128, Box 129, Box 130)
    - Corn Leaf Rhythm, 1945; Print: 14 x 19½; Mount: 16 x 19½
    - Light Echoes, 1970; Print: 10? x 15¾; Mount: 16 x 21
    - Amaryllis Leaf Pod, 1943; Print: 9½ x 11?; Mount: 18 x 19
    - Girl Playing Recorder, 1945; Print: 13? x 9¾; Mount: 20 x 16
    - Le Corbusier In New York, 1946; Print: 10½ x 12?; Mount: 17 x 18
    - Spiral II, 1970; Print: 10? x 11; Mount: 18 x 17
    - Rehearsal Nightmare, 1944; Print: 11¾ x 12?; Mount: 16 x 18
      (Photomontage with Humphrey "Inquest" and Weidman "Daddy Was A Fireman")
    - Professor Joseph Campbell and Student, Sarah Lawrence College, ca. 1953; Print: 9? x 12?; Mount: 14? x 18
    - Dr. Daisetz Teitaro Suzuki, 1958; Print: 12 x 7?; Mount: 18¼ x 14
    - Martha Graham, Lamentation, 1935; Print: 13 x 10½; Mount: 20 x 16
    - City Sound, 1972; Print: 13? x 8?; Mount: 20 x 15
    - Woman's Hand, 1950; Print: 10¼ x 11?; Mount: 16 x 19
    - Martha Graham, War Theme, 1941; Print: 10 x 13?; Mount: 15 x 20
      (to illustrate a poem by William Carlos Williams)
    - Girls Dancing By Lake, Camp Treetops, 1945; Print: 13½ x 10¾; Mount: 20 x 16
    - Walnut, 1943; Macro; Print: 10? x 13½; Mount: 16 x 20
    - Striation I, 1972; Photogram; Print: 19¾ x 13; Mount: 20 x 15
    - Martha Graham, American Document, 1938; Print: 10¾ x 13¼; Mount: 15 x 20
      (Trio - "We Are Three Women - We Are Three Million Women")
    - Our Own House, 1944; Print: 10½ x 12¼; Mount: 16 x 19
    - Girl Sewing, 1948; Print: 10½ x 13½; Mount: 16 x 20
    - Mud and Ice, 1944; Print: 10? x 13?; Mount: 16 x 20
    - Beaumont Newhall Leaping, 1942; Print: 13½ x 10?; Mount: 20 x 15
    - Tree Trunk, 1948; Print: 12? x 10?; Mount: 20 x 15
    - Boy Sharpening Axe, 1945; Print: 13? x 9; Mount: 20 x 15
    - Boy and Hamster, Camp Treetops, 1948; Print: 5¼ x 6½; Mount: 11 x 11
    - Beech Tree IV, Luke Estate, Irvington, New York, 1945; Print: 10¼ x 10¼; Mount: 16 x 17
    - Gerald Heard, 1954; Print: 10½ x 12?; Mount: 16 x 19
    - Serpent Light, 1940; Light Drawing; Print: 9¼ x 12; Mount: 16 x 18
    - Singing In The Rain, Camp Treetops, 1950; Print: 9 x 11?; Mount: 15 x 17
    - Wild Bee Honeycomb, 1943; Print: 7? x 7 7/16; Mount: 16 x 14
    - Corn Tassel Through Broken Windshield, 1967; Photogram-Photomontage; Print: 11? x 10¾; Mount: 15 x 18
    - City Street, 1937; Photomontage; Print: 13¼ x 10; Mount: 18 x 15
    - Goat Begging, Camp Treetops, 1948; Print: 10? x 10¼; Mount: 18 x 15
    - Sand Builders, 1945; Print: 8? x 11¾; Mount: 19 x 17
    - Willard Tossing Cats, 1945; Speedlight; Print: 7? x 13¼; Mount: 14 x 19
    - Hand Stands, 1940; Print: 12? x 7½; Mount: 18 x 14
    - Beech Tree XI, 1945; Print: 12¼ x 7¼; Mount: 18 x 13
    - Martha Graham, American Provincials (Group), 1935; Print: 9 x 10?; Mount: 18 x 13
    - Two Boys and Snake, 1948; Print: 6½ x 9?; Mount: 12 x 14
    - Two Trees, 1950; Print: 9? x 7?; Mount: 14 x 12
    - Nancy Newhall, 1942; Print: 6 x 5?; Mount: 12 x 11
    - Doug with Chicken, 1943; Print: 9¼ x 7¼; Mount: 15 x 12½
    - Girl with Goat, Camp Treetops, 1940; Print: 7? x 9¾; Mount: 14 x 12
    - Boy with Snake, 1944; Print: 7 x 6?; Mount: 12 x 11
    - Boy with Frog, Camp Treetops, 1948; Print: 4½ x 10½; Mount: 15 x 10
    - Inner and Outer Man, 1972; Photomontage; Print: 6? x 4½; Mount: 13 x 11
    - Valerie Bettis, Desperate Heart, 1944; (Photomontage I); Print: 15? x 19?; Mount: 22 x 27
    - Opacities, 1968; Serial Photogram; Print: 18? x 15?; Mount: 26 x 22
    - Pure Energy and Neurotic Man, 1941; Photomontage with Light Drawing; Print: 19 x 15¼; Mount: 27 x 22
    - Martha Graham, Letter to the World (Kick), 1940; Print: 14? x 19½; Mount: 22 x 27
    - Continuum, 1944; Print: 15¼ x 19?; Mount: 22 x 28
    - Doris Humphrey, With My Red Fires ("Matriarch"), 1938; Print: 14¾ x 18¾; Mount: 22 x 26
    - Continuum II (Leaves), 1971; Serial Photogram; Print: 15? x 19?; Mount: 22 x 27
    - Charles Weidman, On My Mother's Side, 1944; Print: 13? x 19¼; Mount: 21 x 27
    - Grape Leaf Dialogue, 1971; Serial Photogram; Print: 14? x 18½; Mount: 22 x 26
    - Amaryllis Seed Pod, 1943; Macro; Print: 12? x 19; Mount: 20 x 26
    - Samadhi, 1940; Light Drawing; Print: 16? x 13?; Mount: 24 x 20
    - Mid-Summer Solstice, 1940; Light Drawing; Print: 15½ x 16?; Mount: 21 x 22
    - Doris Humphrey, Shakers (Humphrey-Weidman Group), 1938; Print: 12? x 14¾; Mount: 20 x 21
    - Helen Tamiris, When The Saints Come Marchin' In (Duet with Daniel Nagrin), 1944; Print: 12? x 15?; Mount: 18 x 21
    - Sumach Leaves, In and Out of Focus, 1945; Print: 12¼ x 15; Mount: 18 x 21
    - Changing Grid, 1970; Serial Photogram; Print: 19¾ x 15½; Mount: 18 x 21
    - Changing Grid, 1970; Serial Photogram; Print: 19¾ x 15½; Mount: 26 x 19
    - Early Southwest Photographs by Barbara Morgan
      - Keel Seel Cliff Dwelling, Willard Morgan, 1928
      - Rito De Los Frijoles, Bandelier National Monument, 1928; Print: 9½ x 6¼; Mount: 14 x 11
      - Willard Morgan on Arch of Rainbow Bridge, 1928; Print: 6¾ x 9?; Mount: 11 x 14
      - Willard Morgan Standing on Rainbow Bridge, 1928; Print: 9? x 6½; Mount: 14 x 11
      - Willard Morgan With view Camera, Mono Lake, California (II), 1929; Print: 6¾ x 9½; Mount: 11 x 14
      - Last Light, Mono Lake, 1929; Print: 6½ x 9?; Mount: 11 x 14
      - Willard Morgan With View Camera, Mono Lake, California (I), 1929; Print: 9¾ x 6¾; Mount: 14 x 11
      - Sand Slide, Mono Lake, California, 1929; Print: 6¼ x 9½; Mount: 11 x 14
    - Erick Hawkins Jumping With Lloyd, 1942; Print: 13? x 9½; Mount: 15 x 19
    - Martha Graham, Frontier, 1935; Print: 9? x 13½; Mount: 16 x 20
    - Fence, 1970; Photogram; Print: 13¾ x 9¾; Mount: 15 x 20
    - City Shell, 1938; Photomontage; Print: 13½ x 9?; Mount: 19¾ x 15¾
    - Beaumont Newhall, 1942; Print: 10? x 11?; Mount: 16 x 20
    - Martha Graham, Deep Song, 1937; Print: 9? x 13½; Mount: 15 x 20
    - Doris Humphrey, To The Dance, 1944; Print: 9? x 12¾; Mount: 16 x 20
    - Marie, 1947; Print: 10 9/16 x 13½; Mount: 16 x 20
    - Willard Morgan Descending Into Canyon De Chelly, 1928; Print: 8? x 12¼; Mount: 14 x 18
    - Diving Off The Dock, 1946; Print: 9? x 13?; Mount: 16 x 20
    - Doris Humphrey, Square Dance (Duet with Charles Weidman), 1938; Print: 10? x 13¾; Mount: 16 x 20
    - Anna Sokolow, The Exile, 1940; Print: 10? x 13?; Mount: 16 x 20
    - Pearl Primus, Speak To Me Of Rivers, 1944; Print: 10¼ x 13¼; Mount: 16 x 20
    - Brothers, 1943; Print: 13¼ x 10½; Mount: 20 x 16
    - Bear Hugging, Camp Treetops, 1947; Print: 10? x 12¾; Mount: 16 x 20
    - Martha Graham, Primitive Mysteries (Group), 1935; Print: 10? x 12?; Mount: 16 x 20
    - Light Waves, 1945; Photogram; Print: 13¾ x 9¾; Mount: 15 x 20
    - Willard's Fist, 1942; Print: 13? x 10¾; Mount: 18 x 20
    - Martha Graham, Primitive Mysteries, 1935; Print: 9½ x 13; Mount: 14 x 19
    - Pearl Lang and Merce Cunningham, Leap, 1944; Print: 7? x 9½; Mount: 14 x 16
    - Girl With Snake, 1948; Print: 9 x 6½; Mount: 14 x 12
    - Girl And Ring Of Water, 1948; Print: 7¼ x 9?; Mount: 12 x 14
    - Three Buddies, 1946; Print: 6? x 9?; Mount: 13 x 14
    - Hanya Holm, Trend (I), 1938; Print: 5¾ x 9¾; Mount: 12 x 15
    - Hanya Holm, Trend (II), 1938; Print: 5? x 9 7/16; Mount: 12 x 15
    - Early Southwest Photographs by Willard Morgan
      - Barbara Morgan in Grand Canyon, 1928; Print: 9½ x 6¾; Mount: 15 x 12
      - Mono Lake, California, 1929; Print: 6? x 9½; Mount: 11 x 14
      - Hopi Indian Ceremonial Eagle, 1928; Print: 9½ x 6?; Mount: 14 x 11
      - Hopi Indian, 1928; Print: 9½ x 6?; Mount: 14 x 11
      - Carreta de Muerto, El Penitente Morado, Trampas, New Mexico, 1928; Print: 7¾ x 8½; Mount: 11 x 14
      - Barbara Morgan Cooking in Canyon de Chelly, 1928; Print: 6? x 9?; Mount: 11 x 14
      - Sand Slide Monolake, Print: 6¼ x 9½; Mount: 11 x 14
  - Mabel Ballin. [Los Angeles(?), ca. 193-].; 2 items. Original photographs.
    [missing 5/2006]
  - *Scenes in Glacier National Park, Montana., 1896.; 7 items. 19.5 x 24 cm. Photographs. Mounted 28 x 35.5. cm. (Box 23)
    Identified and signed on the mat, H.E. Murdock, Minneapolis, Minn.
  - ***Photographs of Latin America. v.p., ca. 1876.; 106 items.
    - [Central America and Mexico], 1875-1976
      The following albumen photographs were taken by Muybridge during his trip to Central America dn Mexico, 1875-1876, after his trial and acquittal for the murder of Major Harry Larkyns. The photographs are marked on the verso in pencil with Muybridge's own numbering system and are so identified below. They measure 13.3 x 23 cm.; mounted and overmatted, 27.5 x 35.5 cm. All are signed in the plate.
      - Panama: An old bridge near the beach., #4267
      - Nicaragua: Narbor scene, Corinto., #4293
      - Salvador: Construction at harbor, La Union., #4297
      - Guatamala: Sea of clouds, Volcan Auga., #4384
      - Guatamala: Lake Atitlan., #4388
      - Guatamala: Streete scene, Mazatenango., #4423
      - Guatamala: Coffee harvest, San Isidrio Plantation., #4455
    - Proof set (35mm.) also taken during his trip to Central America and Mexico., 1875-1876.; 98 photographs. (Box 79)
  - ***[Yosemite photographs.] San Francisco, Bradley & Rulofson, [1872]; 51 plates. (In Photographers Collection)
    Imperfect set. Lacks plate numbers 2, 3, 4, 10, 12, 19, 20, 22, 28, 34, 39 and 47.
    Yosemite National Park - Views.
  - ***Photographers Collection., 3 items. Photographs.
    - Old Man Wang, #168; 13½ x 10 ins.; 34.3 x 26 cm. Silverprint, signed.; mounted and overmated: 53.5 x 50.8 cm.
    - A Mongol, #169; 12 x 9½ ins.; 30.5 x 24.5 cm. Silverprint, signed.; mounted and overmated: 51 x 40.2 cm.
    - El Anciano, #170; 10 x 8 ins.; 24.5 x 20 cm. Silverprint, signed.; mounted and overmated: 51 x 40.2 cm.
  - Photographers Collection., 1 item. Photograph. (Box 80)
  - **Photographers Collection., 2 items. Photographs.
  - Photographers Collection., 3 items. Photographs.
    Greek-American Stathis Orphanos is a Los Angeles writer and photographer. In 1973, he issued his first catalog as a dealer in modern first editions with Ralph Sylvester; in the late 1970s, the two began publishing limited editions. They have published works by Joyce Carol Oates, Paul Bowles, Tennessee William, John Updike, and Gore Vidal, among others. [The Department of Special Collections has most of these publications.] Orphanos's first photographs were taken in 1958 with a Rolleiflex; he now uses a Hasselblad. These first photographs show an awareness of the mystery light gives ordinary objects; and he still considers good the photographs from his first roll of film. He has never had formal training in photography. When a student at California State College, Los Angeles, he was toldy by Dorothy Parker: "You'll have to choose, honey, between writing and photography." For many years he chose writing. With the advent of the publishing he began photography again, since he had contacts with so many important persons. Their reactions have been gratifying, with John Updike having perhaps the highest priase: he felt that Orphanos was giving him the definitive personality he always lacked.
    Orphanos has stated he likes his subject well lit by natural kight, the eyes to show fully, with the subject in focus as much as demon cameras will allow, and in an uncluttered background which works with the foreground ("no lamps coming out of anyone's head"). Actually, his photographs move between two poles of possibility: the world of theatre, costume, and embellished make-believe (such as the portrait of Peggy Christian) and the stark reality of close-up in available light (such as the portrait of Claire Bloom). Orphanos works mainly in black and white and does his own prints, striving to make each print the same. He firmly believes in cropping and darkroom magic.
    A selection of his portraits appeared in The Ontario Review, number 18, Spring-Summer 1983. [The Library Special Collections has a copy of this issue in Collection 527, Stathis Orphanos Papers .]
    - Photograph of Peggy Christina by Stathis Orphanos, 1985 (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Portrait of Peggy Christian by Stathis Orphanos, 1984 (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - [Unititled]. Portrait of Peggy Christian, local Los Angeles bookseller, taken in her shop on La Cienega, Blvd. Los Angeles., circa 1976; Image: 35.5 x 28 cm. (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - [Untitled]. Portrait of Melina Mercouri. Athens., ca. 1984; Image: 29.3 x 24.4. cm.; Mounted and overmatted: 31.5 x 36 cm.
      Inscribed on verso of print by Stathis Orphanos to Peggy Christian.
    - [Untitled]. Portrait of Claire Bloom. n.p., undated.; Image: 25.2 x 20.1 cm.; Mounted and overmatted: 37 x 32 cm.
      Inscribed on verso of print by Stathis Orphanos to Peggy Christian on 3 July 1985.
      Separated Materials note
      The following two items have been removed to Collection 527, Stathis Orphanos Papers 9/98:
      [Untitled]. Portrait of Michael Nava. n.p. undated. 19.4 x 22.7 cm.s Unmounted. Signed by the photographer.
      [Untitled]. Portrait of Michael Nava and Andy Ferrero. n.p. undated. 21.1 x 19.5 cm. Unmounted. Signed by the photographer.
  - **Photographers Collection., 1 item. Photograph.
  - Photographers Collection., 9 photographs. (Box 82)
  - San Diego flume. [San Diego., 1888].; 2 photographs. (Box 82)
    One of the photographs depicts five of six flat bottom boats full of passengers, manyof them with Japanese parasols, riding the flume. Governor Robert Whitney Waterman rides in the first boat with the realtor D.C. Reed.
  - Photographers Collection., 5 photographs. (Box 83)
  - Photographers Collection., ca. 1860-1920?; 73 glass negatives. (Box 119)
    Largely unidentified. Includes portraits of men in navy uniforms, buildings at U.S. Naval Academy ca.1860-1870s, street scenes, early airplanes. Some images may have been taken from publications.
  - Training courses made for Lockheed Industries. [v.p., 1951-1958].; 100 photographs. 20.5 x 25.2 cm. (Box 84)
    Examples from training courses written and produced by Dr. T.K. Peters.
  - ***Pictorialist Collection. v.p., ca. 1916-1935.; 17 items. Original photographs.
    Most of the photographs are signed presentation copies from fellow photographers to Ernest M. Pratt.
    - Mexico., undated.; Rooftop view. 28 x 24 cm. Unmounted.
    - On the Carmelian coast., undated.; Landscape. 34 x 27 cm. Unmounted.
    - The court, Verrochio., 1916.; Architectural view. 24 x 19 cm. Mounted 43.5 x 31.5 cm.
    - Untitled portrait of a small girl., undated.; 22.5 x 18.5 cm. Mounted 43.5 x 31.5 cm.
    - Untitled landscape., 1918.; 24 x 29 cm. Mounted 35.5. x 42 cm.
    - The traveler., 1917.; Portrait. 35 x 25 cm. Unmounted.
    - A war widow., 1918.; Portrait. Toned. 34.5 x 26.5 cm. Mounted 50 x 37 cm.
    - Untitled portrait of a woman., undated.; Toned. 30 x 22 cm. Mounted 51 x 38 cm.
    - Number IV Marine., 1924.; Seascape. 15 x 21 cm. Mounted 38 x 30 cm.
    - Roadside home, Kentucky., undated.; 23 x 18.5 cm. Mounted 37 x 30 cm.
    - The valley beyond our hill., undated.; Landscape. 25 x 19.5 cm. Mounted 45.5 x 32 cm.
    - Untitled portrait of a young boy., undated.; 25 x 19.8 cm. Mounted 45.7 x 31.2 cm.
    - The observatory., 1920.; Architectural view. Toned. 34 x 26.5 cm. Mounted 51.5 x 40 cm.
    - The surf line., 1920.; Landscape. 24.5 x 37 cm. Mounted 35 x 40.5 cm.
    - At San Juan Capistrano., 1920.; Architectural view. 34 x 25 cm. Mounted 51 x 37 cm.
    - Untitled landscape., 25 x 33.5 cm. Unmounted.
    - Snow-clad hills., Landscape. 25 x 33.5 cm. Unmounted.
  - Photographers Collection., 3 boxes, 678 images. [acidic folders, but photos in mylar] (Box 116, Box 117, Box 118)
    The collection consists of modern printsmade fromthe original Pierce negatives.
    - Agriculture - California., 6 photos. (Box 116, Folder 1)
    - Animals., 5 photos. (Box 116, Folder 2)
    - Chinese in California., 9 photos. (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - Descanso Gardens., 10 photos. (Box 116, Folder 4)
    - Deserts - California., 2 photos. (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - Fort Tejon., 1 photo. (Box 116, Folder 6)
    - Kramer Hills., 16 photos. (Box 116, Folder 7)
    - Lincoln, Abraham - Portrait., 3 photos. (Box 116, Folder 8)
    - Los Angeles - Business interiors., 5 photos. (Box 116, Folder 9)
    - Los Angeles - Miscellaneous views., 53 photos. (Box 116, Folder 10)
    - Los Angeles - Parks and botanical attractions., 13 photos. (Box 116, Folder 11)
    - Los Angeles - Schools, churches, government buildings., 17 photos. (Box 116, Folder 12)
    - Los Angeles - Transportation., 11 photos. (Box 116, Folder 13)
    - Los Flores Canyon., 3 photos. (Box 116, Folder 14)
    - Mines and mining., 9 photos. (Box 116, Folder 15)
    - Mission San Antonio de Padua., 2 photos. (Box 116, Folder 16)
    - Mission San Antonio de Pala., 14 photos. (Box 116, Folder 17)
    - Mission San Carlos Boromeo (Carmel), 3 photos. (Box 116, Folder 18)
    - Mission San Fernando., 17 photos. (Box 116, Folder 19)
    - Mission San Gabriel., 3 photos. (Box 116, Folder 20)
    - Mission San Juan Capistrano., 4 photos. (Box 116, Folder 21)
    - Mission San Louis Rey., 23 photos. (Box 116, Folder 22)
    - Mission Santa Barbara., 34 photos. (Box 117, Folder 1)
    - Mission Santa Ysabel., 4 photos. (Box 117, Folder 2)
    - Missions - Miscellaneous., 24 photos. (Box 117, Folder 3)
    - Navajo Indians., 2 photos. (Box 117, Folder 4)
    - Northern California., 7 photos. (Box 117, Folder 5)
    - Oil Wells., 2 photos. (Box 117, Folder 6)
    - Portraits., 24 photos. (Box 117, Folder 7)
    - Ramona., 10 photos. (Box 117, Folder 8)
    - San Diego., 11 photos. (Box 117, Folder 9)
    - San Fernando Valley., 3 photos. (Box 117, Folder 10)
    - San Pedro., 11 photos. (Box 117, Folder 11)
    - Santa Barbara., 4 photos. (Box 117, Folder 12)
    - Santa Monica., 56 photos. (Box 117, Folder 13)
    - Santa Monica., 38 photos. (Box 117, Folder 14)
    - Southern California., 42 photos. (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - Spanish-American War., 18 photos. (Box 118, Folder 2)
    - Texas Rangers., 3 photos. (Box 118, Folder 3)
    - Topanga Canyon., 27 photos. (Box 118, Folder 4)
    - Topanga Canyon., 31 photos. (Box 118, Folder 5)
    - Turner House., 22 photos. (Box 118, Folder 6)
    - Unidentified views - beaches., 3 photos. (Box 118, Folder 7)
    - Unidentified views - buildings., 22 photos. (Box 118, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified views - interiors., 27 photos. (Box 118, Folder 9)
    - Unidentified views - mountains., 8 photos. (Box 118, Folder 10)
    - Venice, California., 3 photos. (Box 118, Folder 11)
    - Warner's Ranch., 10 photos. (Box 118, Folder 12)
    - Yosemite National Park., 12 photos. (Box 118, Folder 13)
  - *Photographers Collection., 6 photographs. 20 x 25.5 cm. mounted, 38 x 46 cm. (Box 8)
    Copies of the earliest known Daguerreotypes of Washington D.C. [1846]: Capitol building with Bulfinch dome; south portico of the White House; Treasury building; two views of an unidentified building. Also, Boston, a view of the Monument to the Battle of North Point.
  - China [pictures]/Eliot Porter; introduction by Jonathan Porter. - New York: DEP Editions, [1985?]; 1 portfolio: laser dye transfer prints; 43 x 54 cm. 7 images, sizes vary. Mounted and overmatted to either 40.5 x 50.5 cm. or 50.5 x 40.5 cm.
    #27 of an edition of 50.
    - Eliot Porter - Images of Nature and Society in China
      The Kong Forest, Confucius's Familey Cemetery, Qufu, Shandong
      Ferry, Chongqing, Sichuan
      Imperial Palace, Peking
      Lotus and Azolla, West lake, Hangzhou, Zhejiang
      Yuantong Monastery, Kumming, Yunnan
      Black Dragon Falls, Lushan, Jiangxi
      Bamboo Grove Near Hangzhou, Zhejiang
  - Photographers Collection., 1 item. Photographs. (Box 29)
  - Photographers Collection., 1 item. Photographs. (Box 85)
  - ***Photographers Collection., Photographs.
  - **Photographers Collection., 1 item. Photographs.
  - ***Photographers Collection., 2 items. Photographs.
    - Queen of Diamonds, 1935; Size/Mounted: 8 x 12 cm./38 x 30 cm.; Cliche-verre(?); silver print mounted on black paper.
    - Stein, Gertrude, ca. 1930; Size/Mounted: 25 x 20 cm./51 x 41 cm.; Silver print
      Gertrude dressed in coat and leopard hat is sitting in wicker chair.
  - Marine Gardens, Avalon, Santa Catalina Island, Calif., 1908. (Box 99)
    9 views of the Marine Gardens on fabric, approximately 18" x 18".
  - Photographers Collection., 1 item. Photographs. (Box 86)
  - Photographers Collection. (Box 134)
    Fifteen 5 x 7 copy prints of California views by Harry Edmond Roberts. There are eight unidentified views of the Mojave Desert area, four of Pam Canyon in Palm Springs, Calif., and one each of a sea shore, a treelined avenue, and a potted plant. All pictures ca. 1914.
  - Photographers Collection., 1 photograph. (Box 87)
  - ***Photographers Collection., 15 items. Photographs.
  - *Mt. Shasta, California., 1884.; 2 items. 21 x 31 cm. Original photographs. (Box 28)
    Mounted 27.5 x 33 cm. Prepared for the U.S. Geological Survey, Fifth Annual Report, with instructions to the printer. Plate XLII: Mt. Shasta, California, from the northeast. Plate L: Foot of Whitney Glacier, Mt. Shasta, California, looking north. Attributed to Russell, who also wrote the Report.
  - ***Photographers Collection., 1 item. Photograph.
    - Portrait, Man, #227; 12 x 9 ins.; 29.5 x 23.2 cm.; Spot of substance on man's eyelid.; mounted and overmatted: 53 x 50.7 cm.
  - ***Photographers Collection., 43 photographs.
    Marilyn Sanders is a Los Angeles writer and photographer. The photographs in this collections are portraits of locally prominent people in the book world: authors, booksellers, printers, etc. The photographs are mounted and overmatted, signed in pencil on the margin of the image, and signed and identified in pen on the back of the mount. Measurements of the images include the margins.
    - "Ward Ritchie, Laguna Beach", ca. 1980.; Image: 34 x 28 cm.; Mounted: 51 x 41 cm. (Box 1)
    - "Jack Smith, June 15, 1980. The Clark Library", ca. 1980.; Image: 36 x 28 cm.; Mounted: 51 x 41 cm. (Box 1)
    - "Jack Zeitlin, Carey McWilliams, John Weaver", ca. 1979.; Image: 28 x 36 cm.; Mounted: 41 x 51 cm. (Box 1)
    - "Norman Corwin", ca. 1976.; Image: 25 x 17 cm.; Mounted: 46 x 36 cm.; Signed in pencil on mount under the image. (Box 1)
    - "John Weaver", ca. 1980.; Image: 36 x 28 cm.; Mounted: 51 x 41 cm. (Box 1)
    - "Jack Zeitlin", ca. 1979.; Image: 36 x 28 cm.; Mounted: 56 x 42 cm. (Box 1)
    - "Ruth Bernhard", ca. 1976.; Image: 25 x 20 cm.; Mounted: 46 x 36 cm. (Box 1)
    - "Bella Lewitzky", ca. 1977.; Image: 36 x 27 cm.; Mounted: 51 x 41 cm. (Box 1)
    - "Image for Antiquarian Fair poster: Cathy", ca. 1981; Image: 27 x 36 cm.; Mounted: 40 x 50 cm. (Box 1)
    - "Ward Ritchie", ca. 1980.; Image: 27 x 36 cm.; Mounted: 41 x 50 cm. (Box 1)
    - "Peggy Christian", 1981; Image: 28 x 36 cm.; Mounted: 51 x 41 cm. (Box 1)
    - "Glen & Muir Dawson", ca. 1981.; Image: 28 x 36 cm.; Mounted: 41 x 51 cm. (Box 1)
      Portrait of the Dawsons standing behind a case in their shop.
    - "Glen & Muir Dawson", ca. 1981.; Image: 28 x 36 cm.; Mounted: 41 x 51 cm. (Box 1)
      Close-up portrait of the Dawsons standing behind a case in their shop.
    - "The Witch's House, B.H. Designed by Harry Oliver, 1921.", Ektacolor photograph.; Image: 24 x 38 cm.; Mounted: 40 x 51 cm. (Box 1)
    - "UCLA Sculpture Garden", ca. 1977; Image: 35 x 28 cm.; Mounted: 51 x 41 cm. (Box 1)
    - "Wo-Men Working Series", 11 items.
      - "Wo-Men Working", ca. 1978; Image: 28 x 36 cm.; Mounted: 41 x 51 cm. (Box 2)